''I've already mastered the 4th Buddha's Palm stance.
我在這里已經住了几個月了 四式如來神掌我都學會了
I miss Sister and Brother Kim Fei
我好想念奶奶和劍飛哥他們
Take me to them!
你帶我下山找他們吧
Silly girl!
傻丫頭
You'll run into your father
如果你去找他們兩個
If you go look for them.''
一定會碰到你爸爸."
I'm going, kiddo.
小妹,走啦
-Take care, Master. -Thanks.
-慢走啊, 師父. -好啊.
Still watching TV, you silly girl?
小妹,你還在看電視？ 你師父都走了,
Your master's leaving!
她不等你啦
Master. Is ''Buddha's Palm'' real?
師父,如來神掌是不是真的
It's just a movie, silly girl.
傻丫頭,那是電影
How can it be real?
哪會是真的?
Master...
師父...
When will you take me off this mountain?
你什么時候帶我下山啊?
When you're all grown up!
等你長大了吧!
I'll have taken you off this mountain by then.
長大了以后師父就帶你下山.
''999--WHO'S THE MURDERER?''
"《999--离奇凶手》"
Come on in! Place your bets!
老板,發財里邊請…玩兩把
Uncle Fat! Good luck!
老板,贏了不少吧,謝謝
-Cho Tat-wah! -Dad!
-喂,曹達華! -爸爸!
Well? Lost again?
怎么了? 又沒錢了?
You already owe us a fortune.
你的錢可真是越欠越多了.
This is not good.
你這樣也不是辦法.
I don't care. You have to pay us back no matter what.
不管怎么樣, 你說什么都要還給我們.
Otherwise...
不然的話...
You'll die for sure, asshole!
你可真會死得很難看!
Dad, the movie is starting!
爸爸…電影快開演了,快點!
Hurry! Hurry!
快點啦!快點啦!
Your wife can be a hooker and you still can't pay!
你這樣賭法,賣了老婆也不夠還的
Brother!
大哥!
Don't worry, Yin.
小燕,你不用怕.
Freeze! There are guns aimed at you everywhere.
別動,到處都有槍對著你.
They're holding Ka Leung hostage and they want me to open the safe.
他們捉走家良,威脅我開保險箱.
Let's go and rescue him, brother!
大哥,快點去救家良吧
It's just a life for a life.
頂多一命換一命
Is there enough time?
還來得及嗎?
It's already 10:50.
現在已經十點五十分了
Last night, there was someone here, wearing a white trenchcoat.
昨天晚上有個穿白色雨衣的人
He went in, and then he left.
進去一會就走了
But no one came and went all day today.
今天,一個人都沒有出入過
That's odd.
這么奇怪?
Someone shot himself in the toilet!!
廁所有人開槍自殺
Dad!
爸爸!
Dad...
爸爸...
Dad, is that you?
爸爸,是不是你?
You came back as a frog so soon?
你這么快變成一只田雞了?
I'll take you home.
我帶你回家吧
Mom! Mom!!
媽媽! 媽媽!
Mom, Dad was killed by ''Crazy'', the guy who runs the gambling place.
媽媽, 其實爸爸 是被那個賭檔門口的大喪殺死的.
I heard him telling Dad the other day,
那天我听見他跟爸爸說,
''I don't care. You have to pay us back no matter what.''
"不管怎樣,你都要還錢給我們."
And he Also said,
還有,大喪說,
''You'll die for sure''!
"如果你還不了這筆錢,這次你死定了"!
It's true!
真的!
Dad was a cop. He wouldn't kill himself!
爸爸以前是保安他不會自殺的,
He wouldn't!!
真的不會!
Mom! Mom!!
媽媽! 媽媽!
Actually, Dad didn't die.
爸爸其實還沒有死.
He only turned into a frog.
他只是變成了一只田雞.
See? it's really him!
你看,這真的是爸爸
Be good and listen to Grandma, understand?
乖乖地听奶奶的話,知道嗎?
Such a big frog hopping around!
這么大的田雞滿街跳
And I just bought this new pair of shoes today!
老子我還特意買了雙新鞋
What's wrong, Boss?
老大,怎么了?
Somebody hit me! Dammit!
這是誰他媽崩我?
Am I bleeding? Am I bleeding??
我有沒有包? 我有沒有包?
Goddamn it!
他媽的!
Don't let me catch you or I'll cut your balls off!
Don't let me catch you or 我一定要廢了你啊!
But no one came and went all day today.
不要給我捉到你啊,我就不叫大喪
That's odd.
這么奇怪？
You think of a way to look inside
你想一個辦法,望一下里邊
and see what's going on.
看一下這里面都在搞些什么？
Brother!
大哥!
Don't worry, Yin.
小燕,你別怕
Freeze! There are guns aimed at you everywhere!
別動,到處都有槍對著你
They're holding Ka Leung hostage and they want me to open the safe.
他們抓走家良,威脅我開保險箱
Why did you kill my master??
你為什么要害死我師父?
Sweet Sugar Cane!
快來買,新鮮的甘蔗!
Come and get it! Crisp and sweet!
來! 又爽又甜又大!
Come and get it! Big and tasty!
來買! 又鮮又香又爽口!
Cut it out, you brat! You're wasting it!
你這臭小子還在這儿鬧,一起玩啊？
They're plump, but cute!
這小姐夠胖,容易生孩子
Nice fishballs!
很好吃的魚蛋!
You know what to do, madam!
走…你這怎么做的,賣魚蛋的
Good business, granny!
生意不錯,婆婆!
Let me get a cane!
我來拿根甘蔗!
Hands off! I get first pick!
我還沒拿,你拿什么?
-Here you are. -Thank you.
-來...喝茶... -謝謝.
-The canes look good! -Help yourself.
-你的甘蔗挺好吃的! -拿去吃.
Each of you, take one.
拿去吃, 拿去吃.
What? You don't know me?
看什么看,不認得我?
Quit staring, sugar cane kid!
還看什么賣甘蔗小子!
Your dad still owes me money, you know!
你爸爸欠我錢我還沒跟你算呢!
Keep staring and I'll break you in half,
再看我打斷你的腿,
just like a sugar cane.
長得像根捧錘似的.
You should take him to see a doctor!
有空帶他看醫生吧!
Bye now. Have some more.
拿走…拿去嘗嘗
-Where are you going now? -Hey! Come back and help me!
-臭小子你又去哪? -喂! 快回來幫忙!
Fantastic!
哇，好勁啊!
It's really big!
真的好大呀!
Bigger than your mom's!
喂，比你媽還大!
If we could just see the girl
如果我們能見到她出來
and see her taking it in with her own fair hands,
然后就見到她 用手輕輕的撫摸著自己的頭發
that would be great!
那樣多好啊!
Let's wait a while then.
我們等一下看她出來啊？
Let's go! She could be an old hag!
走啦，哥哥! 這個是阿婆的啊!
Let's go!
走...走啦!
I say we stone it to death!
我說用塊石頭砸死它!
I say we bury it alive. That's more fun!
我說挖個洞把它活埋了更過癮!
No, let's do this.
我玩過了.
Let's drown it and see how long it can last.
把它淹在水里邊看能撐多久.
How about...
照我說...
Death by electrocution?
用電電死它?
You're weird!
你這么變態!
How come there's nothing?
-怎么沒有反應? -就是
Why's that?
沒有水怎么通電?
You need water!
對!
Let's get some then!
我們去找水吧!
We can just pee on it!
用不著,撒泡尿下去不就行了!
Come on!
來…
I'm in deep shit!
哇，你就出這种注意啊？
I can't feel my little brother!
我感覺小弟弟都不是我自己的!
What?
什么啊?
You little brother is right there!
你都撒到那邊啦!
No that one! THIs one!
那個啊？ 這個啊!
You're kidding!
不會吧!
How dare you play on our turf, kid?
小子,敢來我的地頭玩?
Don't you know who we are? Which gang do you belong to?
找死? 你們哪的?
Well?
不說話是吧?
Then we have to give all of you a beating!
不說話就一人打一拳才能走
What do you say? Who says this is your turf?
關你什么事,誰說這是你的地方?
I'll take you! One on one!
不服气我們就單挑,擺什么臭架子?
Motherfucker! See how cocky he is?
媽的! 這么囂張?
Let's cut the bullshit and kill him first!
先扁了他再跟老大說 別跟他說那么多!
Why are you in such a fucking rush?
你別這么衝動行不行?
Let me find out who he is first, then I'll kick his ass!
讓我問問清楚再揍他也不遲
Kid, you better not fuck with me.
臭小子別在我面前裝蒜.
Tell me which gang you belong to or I'll fuck you up!
如果你今天不說清楚的話 我肯定把你打個半死!
So you want to fight me, huh? Get me my knife!
還想跟我單挑? 好,拿把刀來!
Yes, Boss!
是, 老大!
Here, Boss!
老大,給你刀!
It's a fake! Get them!
假的!抓住他們!
''THE BOXER FROM SHANTUNG''
"馬永貞 - 鐵拳能劈六腳"
Showtime!
進場!
Watch the stall. I have to go get some more cane.
你看著,我再拿些甘蔗來
Hey. Have you seen it yet?
喂,你看了沒有?
Of course not! Grandma wouldn't let me go out!
看個屁! 奶奶都不讓我走開!
You're missing out!
你不看真是可惜!
Don't you know? Mario Milano is in it!
你知道嗎? 是君子馬蘭奴演的!
He has a fight with Ma Wing Jing.
他跟馬永貞那場擂台比武
It's awesome!
真的很精彩!
Really?
不是吧?
Milano uses his Cobra Lock on Ma!
馬蘭奴用他那招毒蛇鑽鎖住馬永貞!
Ma turns around and uses his ''Tiger's Tail Kick''!
馬永貞來個回馬肘,一個虎層腳!
So who wins?
最后誰贏了?
Ma Wing Jing, of course!
當然是馬永貞了!
Watch the stall, mom!
媽,你看著!
You brat! Come back here, now!
臭小子,你又野到哪去!
See that girl? She's gorgeous!
那個小姐很漂亮
Yeah, just like the heroine in ''A Touch Of Zen''!
是,像俠女一樣
Did you see that? She smiled at me!
看見了吧?,她對著我笑呢
She was looking at me, silly!
你有病,她對我笑呢
She looked this way!
你看,這么看過來的
Look over there!
你看…,看那邊看吧,
YOU look over there!
你自己看吧!
Greetings, everyone!
各位街坊鄰居,叔伯兄弟
I'm delighted
今天很高興
to demonstrate for you
讓小弟趁這個机會
my Twin Butterfly Knives stances!
耍一套蝴蝶雙刀給大家看看
But before I do, my daughter would like to give you something.
還沒耍之前就讓小女發點東西給大家
Please come and visit my school.
有空就來我這儿玩玩
I guarantee that you'll be heaIthier and more fit!
保証你健脾開胃,瘦子變胖子
Come and visit us.
有空上來看看
Your drumming was great!
剛才你打鼓好捧
-Come and visit us. -Sure.
-有空上來看看. -好啊.
It's the Hung Gar Fist!
哇,洪拳!
Your horse stance has to be lower!
馬步要扎得穩! 低一點!
Harder!
用點力!
Where's your strength?
沒吃飯啊?
Hey, it's here!
嘿, 是這里啊!
''Gok's Martial Arts School''
"葛彪國術館"
Come on!
上去啦!
-Are you sure about this? -Yes!
-真的要學? -是啊!
You might as well learn something!
整點本事,反正聞著也聞著
Hey! Wai!
喂! 阿威!
Where did you learn that move?
這招是什么?哪學來的?
From watching ''The Boxer From Shantung'', Master.
師父,看《馬永貞》學來的
Always watching Kung Fu films!
一天到晚看這些武打片
It's all fake! They don't know how to fight!
全是假的,真的那么容易打?
They fight and fight, but no one dies!
打…打…打,不死嗎?
That actor, Chen Kuan Tai? He practices cuIt stances!
陳觀秦只是《大圣劈封門》
He knows nothing about Hung Gar Fist!
哪會什么洪拳!
Now go to the corner and practice your horse stance!
兩個滾到那邊牆角,扎馬!
-Dad. -What?
-爸爸. -干嘛?
We have new students.
有人上來學功夫.
What do you want to learn?
上來學什么?
The Butterfly Knives.
我想學蝴蝶刀
Why?
學來干什么?
For rev -
學來報...
To protect the country, strengthen my body,
保國安家,強身健体
and to glorify our Chinese Martial Arts!
把中國武術發揚光大
At least you have some ambition.
你倒挺有志气
And you?
你呢?
I want to learn drumming!
我想學打鼓
Drumming?
打鼓?
Yes, I want to learn this beautiful tradition of Cheung Chau Island
是,我想學這种优秀的傳統藝術
so that we will become famous throughout Asia,
將來可以代表長洲,衝出亞洲
Africa, and even Europe!
奔向非洲,打到歐洲
Then do you know the rules of learning kung fu here?
那你知不知道學功夫要遵守什么?
Read them out aloud!
你們給我大聲地念出來
One, respect our Master.
第一條,一定要尊師重道
Two, protect our country.
第二條,保國安家
Three, help the weak.
第三條,鋤強扶弱
Four, always help others.
第四條,見義勇為
Five, pay tuition on time.
第五條,准時交錢
Good!
好!
Get the Butterfly Knives, honey.
女儿,替我把蝴蝶雙刀拿出來.
Here, Dad.
爸爸,刀
These knives have a long history.
這對蝴蝶雙刀,大有來頭.
I inherited them from my Master. They are the symbol of our school.
是我師父傳給我做為鎮館之寶用的
I'll tell you their glorious history later.
以后有空再告訴你它的有多厲害.
I'll just let you hold them today.
今天先讓你們拿一拿.
I want you two to really learn your crafts here.
以后你們倆就在這儿用心學習吧.
Honey, fill out the registration forms for them.
女儿,帶他們倆到那邊辦理登記手續.
So you're Master Gok's daughter!
原來你是葛師父的女儿!
What's your name?
怎么稱呼?
I'm Nam.
叫我阿南吧
How old are you?
你几歲了?
I just want to know whether you're older than me.
沒什么,我看你大還是我大
If you are, then I'll call you Big Sister.
你大我就叫你師姐,
If you aren't, then I'll call you Little Sister.
比我小我就叫你師妹
Just call me Nam.
叫我阿南行了
Nam? I'm Ming.
阿南? 我叫阿明
Everyone calls me ''Fishball Ming''.
這里人人全都叫我"魚蛋明"
He is Fan.
他叫阿凡.
How many days do you plan to attend each week?
你打算一星期學几個晚上?
Two.
兩個晚上.
Only two days?
兩個晚上這么少?
You won't learn much with two lessons a week.
這么少什么都學不到.
I'll make it five a week.
五個晚上吧.
But two is fine for learning drums.
你只學打鼓兩個晚上差不多了.
No! I'll learn kung fu too!
不…我也學功夫
Five days for me too!
五個晚上啦
She didn't ask you to learn kung fu!
她沒叫你學!
I want to keep you company!
什么,我陪你學!
I don't need your company!
誰要你陪!
What about your sugar cane job?
你不用賣甘蔗嗎?
Oh no!
糟了!
I must have hurt it when we electrocuted that rat!
你知道嗎，電老鼠的時候， 電傷了小弟弟啦？
What?
啊?
I was this close to ''Chivalrous Lady''.
我剛才靠近俠女的時候，
But I wasn't even aroused!
一點反應也沒有啊!
I must have killed all the nerves!
我想一定是電死了小弟弟的神經啦!
Really? That can be serious!
不是吧? 你不是說笑吧!
Of course it is! I can't make it go bigger!
我的小弟弟不會大，只會小! 難道不是電死了神經啊？
What if l become...impotent?
我是不是...噓...虛弱啦?
All right.
好啦.
Go and catch the aduIt show tomorrow morning.
你听我說，明天早上去看成人電影，
I guarantee you'll be fine afterwards.
我保証你就會沒事的...
Really?
是不是真的啊?
Trust me.
好啦，相信我啦.
So whenever you're near girIs, you'll go like this?
不管在哪邊你靠近女孩子 都會像這樣！
Why? Don't you?
什么啊? 你不也是嗎?
''THE VlRGlN FLOWER BLOOMS''
"玉女含苞朵朵開"
Well? Could you?
喂? 怎么樣啊?
Give me a cane.
給我根甘蔗.
See! Of course l still could!
看! 當然我還是行的!
See? I told you!
嘿? 是什么啊!
That was a great idea!
有辦法啦!
Good business, boss!
老板,生意不錯吧!
Good business, granny!
婆婆,生意不錯吧!
Thanks.
謝謝.
What's with you?? All those fancy movements!
你搞什么? 又吊步又蹲馬的...
What a waste of time!
...浪費時間
It's just an Unicorn Dance! Watch me!
不就是舞個麒麟嗎,拿過來
Look. Just wave it like this!
看著,左搖搖右晃晃不就行了嗎
Idiot!
像根捧錘似的是
Start the cymbaIs!
起鑼鼓!
Good business!
賣魚蛋的,生意不錯吧!
Good business, granny!
婆婆,生意好嗎？
-This is for you. -Thanks.
-拿去喝茶. -謝謝.
Have a sugar cane.
拿去吃吧.
What's your problem, sugar cane boy?
看什么？賣甘蔗小子,
Always giving me that stare!
Always giving me that stare! 每次都瞪著我
Come to the Temple tonight, if you dare.
看我不順眼,晚上到大廟來找我
Normally, I would go all the way down.
本來這招要全蹲下的
But since I've split my pants, I'll just go halfway.
我褲子開線了先蹲下一半
Whoever wins tonight will work for me.
今天晚上打贏的那個以后就跟著我混
Whoever loses will have to fix my pants.
打輸了那個給我補褲子
Let me make it clear. It'll be a no-holds-barred match.
先說清楚了,各憑本事打死無怨
-Curly! -Here.
-鬃毛強! -這里.
What's your stance again?
你那套叫什么?
The Mantis Fist!
螳螂片橋
-Sounds good. Let's see it. -Yes.
-挺好听的. 耍給我看看. -是.
Good, good.
好, 好,好… 打得好,打得好
-Baldy! -Here!
-光頭仔! -這里!
What's your style?
你那套叫什么?
The Nine Pa Mei Pushes.
白眉九步推
Sounds good. Let's see it.
挺好听,耍來看看
Good, good.
好, 好,好… 打得好,打得好
We'll have a ''Mantis Fist vs The Nine Pa Mei Pushes'' tonight.
今天晚上就螳螂片橋對白眉九步推
Begin! We'll watch it from up there.
開始,我上去看看
What the fuck are you two doing?
你們兩個干什么啊?
Just fight!
開始啊,打啦!
What the hell was that?? Choy Li Fut style?
打蔡李佛啊？
Use your Mantis Fist and your Nine Pa Mei Pushes!
打螳螂拳和九步推啊!
Where are your styles now?
你們兩個哪個門派的?
Clobber him!
一拳打下去!
Arm lock!
鎖他的喉!
Hit his head...
打他的頭...
Are you all right, Boss?
老大, 你沒事吧?
-Again?? -Oh no!
-又來了?? -糟了!
It's not bleeding! It's not bleeding!
…有沒有流血啊？ 沒有流血
Motherfucker!
他媽的!
Come down here and fight me if you dare!
有种的下來跟我單挑!
Hiding like a goddamn turtle!
縮頭烏龜躲起來,沒死用!
Fuck you! Go to Hell!
操! 我定要廢了你!
Don't let me catch you or I'll cut your balls off!
你不要給我捉到,我就不叫大喪!
You're all fucking useless!
你們他媽這些飯桶夏沒用!
It's been more than 10 years now and you still can't find him!
叫你們幫我把他找出來 找了十几年還找不到!
Do you want him to crack my head open?
是不是等他把我頭打破了你們才高興?
Bastards! All you know is eating and shitting!
王八蛋,一個個全都是吃屎拉飯的!
Keep fighting!
繼續打!
That's weird!
這么邪門!
Yup. She just disappeared.
真的,昨天晚上她真的不見了
You should come with me tonight.
今晚上陪我再去一次吧.
What are you doing?
說話呀
Can't you see? I'm practicing the ''Golden Fire Eyes'' magic!
你沒看見嗎?我在練金睛火眼
Don't worry. Once I master it,
你放心,等我練成金睛火眼
I'll be able to spot all ghosts and demons!
什么邪魔歪道一眼就能看出來!
-''JAMES BOND in LlVE AND LET DIE'' -Are you for real?
-"鐵金剛勇闖毒龍潭" -吹牛不眨眼
Is this the right way?
這是什么地方?
Yes. Come on!
走吧,等等我
What is this place?
到底是什么地方
It should be here.
應該是這儿
This is getting scary!
不對勁,這里越來越恐怖
Who cares? Come on!
管它呢,走吧
Who would live here?
哪有人住這种地方?
Fan, what is this place?
阿凡,你是不是弄錯了?
Are you sure you're on the right path?
越走越恐怖,有沒有走錯路?
No one would live here!
哪有人住在這种地方?
I told Mom I'd be home for dinner!
不行,我答應我媽回家吃飯的
Let's go. We'll come another time.
走吧,下次再來吧
Hey! Are you all right?
喂! 沒事吧?
She has to be a ghost!
沒錯的,她肯定是一只女鬼
No way.
不會吧?
Think about it. Why would a pretty girl like that
你想想看,在這荒山野岭
live in the woods?
怎么會住著一個像你所說的美女呢?
Also, when I fell last night...
還有,你知不知道...
Do you know what I saw?
我昨天掉下樹林的時候我發現什么啊?
What?
什么啊?
An abandoned graveyard!
我發現了一座荒廢的墳墓
The coffins are covered with weeds. Some of them were even half opened!
有一半還裂開了,周圍被野草蓋著
I was about to look closer
我剛想撥開來看看
when I saw a long-haired girl in white.
就見一個穿著白袍
She floated towards me.
頭發長長的女孩飄呀…地飄過來
Then, with a puff of smoke, she turned into a fox,
呼的一聲又變成了一只狐狸
and she entered one of the coffins! I almost pooped in my pants!
還鑽進那墳墓里,嚇得我屁滾尿流
Yeah right, and Wu Kum played the fox!
是…那只狐狸叫胡精
Try to kid me, huh?
你耍我
And blocked me?
你還擋?
Let's go see Master tonight
今儿晚上上師父那里
so he can fix your arm.
叫師父給你看看手吧
You should ask him to fix your nose!
你叫師父先替你整整鼻子吧
You just want to see ''Chivalrous Lady''. She wouldn't talk to you!
你要見俠女嘛,她不理你
Just go and let him take a look!
去吧,弄弄它,
Otherwise you'll become a cripple!
不然會殘廢的!
Your nose will rot!
你會爛鼻子!
Your arm will fall off!
你斷手啊!
Your face will have scars!
你毀容!!
You won't be able to peeI canes!
你削不了甘蔗!
No squeezing fishballs for you!
你捏不了魚蛋!
You two monkeys! You've been watching too many Kung Fu films!
你們兩個兔崽子! 一定是整天在外面看武打片!
You think you're Kung Fu stars now?
你們以為自己是武打明星?
Here, Dad.
爸爸.
Starting fights all the time!
一天到晚跟人家在外面打架
You think you can fight? Just because you know a few moves
很能打嗎? 別以為自己學了几招功夫會兩下子
doesn't mean you can!
就能打了很了不起了
Let me tell you.
我告訴你們.
Those Kung Fu films? They are all fake!
那些武打片全都是騙人的!
No way, Master.
不是吧,師父?
Of course!
誰說不是
Who's that director?
那個什么導演
Chang Cheh!
張徹!
In all of his films,
拍的每部片子,
they all fight with their guts all falling out!
個個打得腸破血流還打不死!
Cut off someone's arm and he becomes the ''One Armed Swordsman''!
沒了一只手叫《獨臂刀》
Their guts are all spilled out,
給斧頭剖開肚子腸子都流出來了
but they just hold them in and keep on fighting!
拿在手里還不停地打…也沒事
Isn't that ridiculous?
太夸張了吧?
Then there's the worst of the lot!
最离譜是那部什么
Starring Ti Lung and David Chiang...
狄龍跟姜大偉拍的,什么仇?...
What's it called? ''Ven...''
什么仇啊?...
''Vengeance''
《報仇》
Right! ''Vengeance''!
對! "《報仇》"!
All it talks about is revenge!
日報夜報,整部電影都是說要報仇!
What a bad model for kids!
教坏小孩子!
And Chang Cheh even won Best Director for it!
還讓他拿了第十六屆亞洲影展 最佳導演!
All of you monkeys like to watch those films.
你們這些兔崽子就去看這些電影
How can you not turn bad?
怎么不學坏呢?
Wrap his arm.
去給他上藥
I'll come back and tell you the history of the Butterfly Knives.
回頭再給你們說蝴蝶刀的典故
Does it hurt?
疼不疼?
A little.
有一點.
I want some too!
我也要敷!
How? You've got too many cuts.
你割得像豆腐花一樣,怎么敷?
Then...you can at least rub on it!
那...揉揉也好啊
Later.
等一下吧.
I inherited this pair of Butterfly Knives from my Master.
這對蝴蝶雙刀就是我師父傳給我的.
Back then, during a martial arts tournament,
當年我師父就在這個武林大會上,
my Master used it against the Master of the 9-ringed Sword.
跟另一位大師的九環刀 用這對雙刀和他比武.
However...
沒想到...
At the tournament, my Master...
沒想到我師父他就在武林大會上...
My Master lost.
沒想到我師父輸了
The 9-ringed Sword became more popular.
讓九環刀列入十八般兵器里
My Master feIt very guiIty.
他覺得很內疚.
He knew it wasn't the Butterfly Knives,
因為他覺得,不關刀的事,
it was because of his own imperfect skills that failed them.
只是當時自己學藝未精,負了雙刀.
Therefore, my Master decided to make these two Butterfly Knives
所以我師父就把這對蝴蝶雙刀
the heirloom of our school.
當作傳家之寶
It is to remind us
就是要警惕我們
that we should never assume that we're the best!
別老是以為自己是世上最厲害的!
Do you understand?
你們明不嗎?
Yes!
明白!
Keep practicing!
練功!
995, 996, 997...
995, 996, 997...
998, 999, 1000.
998, 999, 1000.
-Your turn! -Why?
-該你了! -干什么?
Why? You think I'm a retard?
干什么? 你當我白痴啊?
A little kid like him can't kick that hard!
他個子那么小怎么會踢那么大勁?
You must have kicked it! Come on!
一定是你踢的啦,進去!
Thanks.
謝謝.
''NOW SHOWlNG''
"即日放映"
''ClNDERELLA''
"仙侶奇緣"
Sugar canes! Sweet and crisp!
來買,又甜又脆又大根的甘蔗
It's you?!
是你?!
Were you fighting again?
你又和人打架了?
-I'll help you. -No need!
-我幫你搽啊？. -不用了!
You're looking for me?
咦,你來找我?什么事?
Have some fishballs!
先吃一串魚蛋吧
Dad told me to come and collect your fees.
沒啊,我爸叫我來跟你收學費
You're way overdue.
你過期很久了.
That's all?
就這事?
I only have small change. Do you mind?
我只有零錢你要不要?
Hey!
喂!
I didn't mean to peek at you the other night.
那天晚上我不是故意偷看你的.
But I was lost, so...
不過我迷了路,
And I saw your house.
所以無意中發現你住的地方...
There was light upstairs,
我見到樓上有光,
so I climbed up the tree to see if somebody's there.
我就爬上樹看看屋里有沒有人.
That's when I saw you.
所以就無意中看見你了.
But I didn't see anything!
但是我真的什么也看不見!
Really! I swear I didn't see anything!
真的,什么也沒看見!
You're not a ghost, right?
你真的不是鬼?
You live with them?
你和她們住一塊?
You live in a nunnery?
你住那儿是不是尼姑庵?
Yes. So?
是又怎么樣?
Then...What's your name?
那...你叫什么名字?
Why should I tell you?
為什么要告訴你?
If you won't tell me, then...
你不告訴我
I'll come back tonight and ask you again.
那我今晚上再來問你...
I dare you!
你敢?
You just wait and see.
你試試.
I'm the Decimator, how's that?
我叫滅絕師太,行了吧?
Decimator? I'm Fan.
滅絕師太?我叫阿凡
You're a nuisance!
好煩啊!
What's your phone number, Decimator?
滅絕師太你給我電話啊
What now? I don't have a phone!
你又想怎么樣,我沒有電話
No phone? So how do I find you?
你沒有電話?那我怎么找你?
Why don't you give me your address? I'll write you letters
要不你把地址給我,我寫信給你
and I'll deliver them myself!
那我就親自送給你了
Just mail it to the convenience store down the hill.
你寄到山腳雜貨店吧
Use your strength!
用力啊!
1 , 2, 3...
1 , 2, 3...
Hey, hey! Give me a hand.
喂, 喂! 幫幫忙啊.
Are you really going to write to that ghost?
你真的打算寫信給那個女鬼?
Just burn her some paper money as offerings!
不要吧,你燒點紙錢給她不就算了
You won't even help me?
這么沒有義气,幫個忙也不行?
Fine. Give me back my swimming pants!
那你把泳褲還給我
Give it to me!
拿來吧,快點
Thanks.
謝謝.
I'm done.
寫好了.
''I fell in love
"當我第一眼看見你的時候
the first time I saw you''
便愛上了你"
That's too direct, you jerk!
臭小子,這么直接!
But you did! Just admit it!
是真的嘛,不承認!
Can it be something less direct
不,有沒有間接一點
and more romantic?
有點浪漫的?
Think!
再想想看吧!
''MELODY''
"兩小無猜"
I've got it!
有辦法!
You read and I'll write.
來,你念我抄.
''A young couple with a lack of family warmth...''
"一對少年男女在缺乏家庭溫暖之下..."
Too fast!
這么快,怎么寫?
Okay, slowly...
好,慢點...
''A young couple...
"一對少年男女...
How do you spell ''couple''?
"對"字怎么寫?
Just look!
自己看吧!
''MISS DEClMATOR. STORE BY THE HlLL, LANTAU ISLAND''
"大嶼山鹿湖山腳雜貨店滅絕師太收"
Well?
怎么辦啊?
''THE FRUIt Is SWELLlNG''
"蜜桃成熟時"
What do we write now?
怎么寫啊?
How about this?
要不試試看這么寫?
''When a peach swells,
"一個蜜桃在它成熟的時候,
it's sweet and juicy.
又甜又多汁的.
Every man who sees it
每個男人看見它
will be overcome with passion.
都會欲望奔流恬不自禁.
I've always longed for a peach.
我也很想擁有一個蜜桃.
I wonder if yours is swelling?''
不知道你成熟了沒有?"
-Juicy my ass! -I'm just fantasizing!
臭小子!成熟蜜桃,我打死你!
Don't you want that yourself?
想想而已,你不想嗎?
''GlRIfRlEND''
"女朋友"
Here are the synopses of all the movies we've shown.
這間戲院上映過的影片, 全都在這儿了
Thanks, Uncle Kew.
多謝,喬叔
-Take your time. -Okay.
-好,你們慢慢看吧 -好.
There are so many here!
這好多!
These synopses will last us a lifetime!
這么多戲,一輩子也寫不完啊!
Look at this!
喂,看看這個!
Which one is this?
是什么?
''999--WHO'S THE MURDERER''?
《999离奇凶手》？
That's an old one!
這部電影很老了
It's been almost 10 years.
差不多有十年了!
I think it starred Cho Tat-wah and Lin Fung.
好像是曹達華和林鳳主演的
During its run, his dad...
我還記得電影放映的時候, 他爸爸在廁所...
My dad didn't kill himself! He was murdered!
我爸不是自殺,他是被人謀殺的
Why wouldn't any of you believe me??
為什么你們都不相信?
Dinner at 7,
倒牌,倒不倒?倒不倒牌?
then I'll take you to see something exciting at 10.
來…你的 到時候吃完飯十點帶你去看好東西
I'll pick you up at 7. Where do you live?
七點到樓下接你, 你住哪里啊?
That's it! Just attack his head!
加油…就這么打
Where are your strengths??
這樣才對要用力打下去
On the ground! Roll!
你摸來摸去算什么,真是
Sweep him over!
你掃膛腿要掃他,短兵器接長兵器
What're you afraid of? Just stab him!
你怕什么,你插他,我告訴你
Chop him up! Yes!
砍他…對了
You're so violent!
你怎么那么殘忍!
We don't have to watch it!
不愛看就喝汽水,好不好!
You want some soda?
來…喝汽水吧
I'll buy you a soda.
請你喝汽水?
No soda? We can go and catch some crabs!
不喝汽水,捉螃蟹吧!
I'll call you!
我打給你!
And to think I bought a new hat just for her!
害我花几塊錢還買頂帽子!
Bastard! Not again?!
我干你娘!又來了?
Don't just stand there!
去找他,楞著像根捧錘似的!
Wait! Am I bleeding?
喂,我有沒有流血?
Go! Find him!
沒有,就快去找他!
Fan?! What are you doing here?
阿凡,你在這儿干嘛?
So it was ''Crazy'' who killed your dad.
原來大喪就是你的殺父仇人
No wonder you hate his guts.
怪不得你這么恨他
You believe me?
你真的信我啊?
Of course!
信,當然相信
You never joke around about your dad!
難道爸爸可以隨便拿來開玩笑嗎?
Nobody likes that asshole ''Crazy''.
大喪那混蛋在這儿一向臭名頂頂的
Everyone wants him dead!
這誰不想他早點死
As long as you believe me.
有你信我就行了
But...do you have any proof?
不過...你有沒有証据啊?
Of course! I saw him crush my dad to death!
証据?我親眼看他踩死我爸爸的,証据
He crushed your dad?
踩死你爸爸?
You won't understand.
你不會明白的
He killed my dad.
是他害死我爸爸的
I must take revenge for him.
我一定要替我爸爸報仇
But you'll be in trouble if you kill him.
但是,殺了他我們會很麻煩的
You better think it over.
你還是先想清楚吧
I'll break his head!
我一定要打破他的頭
No one will know.
沒有人會知道的
Let me do it then! I hate him too!
你讓我試試看,我也很恨他
-Really? -Sure!
-真的? -是啊!
-Give it to me!
-拿來啊!
Don't just stand there! We're not catching birds here!
你站著看什么?偷鳥?
Point that flashlight around!
到處照照,這里照照那里也照照
Look everywhere!
到處找找吧!
Why are you pointing it at the Temple, asshole?
混蛋,你照北帝廟干什么?
The rock came from there!
石頭是從那邊射過來的!
What's wrong, Boss?
老大,沒事吧?
It hurts!
好痛!好痛!
This was even worse!!
他媽的,這回一身雞卵了
What are you doing tonight?
你晚上去哪?
I'm meeting up with Hou.
約了小猴子.
Hou?
小猴子?
Can you take me to see this movie?
你能不能帶我看這部電影?
Su...Sure. Let's go.
那...好啊,走吧
See? I told you this was a good synopsis!
我早說這故事寫得好了啊
Mr. Kuen.
權叔
One cane, please.
來一根甘蔗.
Get it yourself!
你自己來啊!
Hey. Aren't you showing ''ROMEO AND JULlET''?
喂. 什么事啊？ 不是放"殉情記"嘛?
It ended yesterday.
昨天演完了.
Yesterday?
演完了?
Holy shit. That's not good.
唉,沒得看了.
''At 1 1 :30 am, President Nixon and his wife got off the plane.
"上午11時30分 尼克松總統和夫人等走下飛机.
The President examined the PLA along with Premier Chou En-lai.''
尼克松總統由周恩來總理陪同, 檢閱了中國人民解放軍陸海空三軍儀仗隊."
You know what? That was my very first movie.
你知不知道,這是我第一次進戲院看電影
We'll go see it when they show it again.
等那個電影重播的時候我再和你看.
Great! I love the actress.
好,我很喜歡里面的女主角.
Her name is Olivia Hussey.
她的名字叫奧莉花荷西.
Those pictures you sent me were beautiful.
你寄給我的照片很美.
You like them?
你喜歡?
I'll ask Uncle Kew for more and send to you.
我下回找橋叔問他多拿一些寄給你.
Okay. Don't forget!
那好,你記住!
You...why do you live in a nunnery?
你...為什么會住在尼姑庵?
My dad was very poor when l was born.
我剛生下來的時候,我們家的環境不是很好
Back then, a fortune-teller said
那個時候有一個神婆
that my birth stars clashed with his,
她說我的命會克我爸我媽,
so they sent me here.
所以我就搬來這里了.
Do you know this plant?
你知不知道這個是什么草?
It's called ''Ghost Needles''.
這种草叫"鬼針草".
Once fermented, you can use it to cure arthritis.
如果用來泡酒對醫治風濕骨病根有效的.
And do you know this one?
你知不知道這是什么草?
No.
不知道.
This is ''Chicken Droppings Vine''.
這种草叫"雞屎藤".
Perfect for making good preserves.
這個用來做茶果,味道很好.
You're like a little old lady!
你挺像個老太婆的!
What?
什么?
I have some ointment.
我有万金油.
No, thanks.
不用了.
So you've always lived here?
你一直住這儿?
Yes, my Master is very nice to me.
是,師父對我很好
She takes care of me and lets me study,
又疼我,又讓我讀書
but she wouldn't let me go out and play.
不過,就是不許我出去玩
Do you have any friends?
那你不是沒有朋友了?
Sure. You've seen them.
也有,你也見過的
I have?
我見過?
Then, will you become one of them?
那你以后會不會做那個?
A nun?
尼姑?
I don't know. Maybe.
不知道,也許吧
Look!
你看!
I have to go back now.
我要回去了.
Can you loan me your jacket?
能不能把你的牛仔衣給我穿?
Thank you for your birthday gift.
那就謝謝你的生日禮物了.
Birthday gift?
生日禮物?
I don't know when my birthday is,
我也不知道什么時候生日,
but...I like it to be today.
不過...我喜歡今天是生日.
When can I see you again?
我什么時候可再來見你?
The day after tomorrow.
后天吧.
You changed your hair style today.
你今天鬈了頭發.
When can I see you again?
我什么時候可以再見你?
''FUNERAIs FOR JULY''
"七月葬禮"
Fan, you're so compassionate!
阿凡,你真有心!
And at such a young age!
想不到你年紀這么輕就這么懂事!
My condolences, Auntie.
七嬸,節哀順變.
Are you coming to the burial too?
會儿你要不要跟我們上山?
Two tickets. Seats K15 and K16.
K15、K16,兩張
We'll stuff this bean
我們將黃豆
into the rat's ass.
塞進老鼠的屁眼里.
Then we'll let it go.
然后把它放回家.
Once the bean expands,
等那些黃豆慢慢…地發大,
it will block its asshole.
堵住它的屁眼.
It can't shit, so it'll go crazy
叫它拉不出屎, 憋…得發瘋
due to constipation,
由于便秘,
and end up biting its family to death!
就把一家大小全都咬死了!
We can then collect the bodies!
到時候我們就慢慢收尸了!
Will it work? Who told you this?
你听誰說的?是不是真的?
My Grandma!
听我外婆說的!
She says it's a long lost art!
這套絕技在江湖上失傳很久了!
You don't believe me? Try it!
你不信試試看!
Let's try it.
好…那就來吧.
Hey you!
喂,蛋仔!
You guys fought with our boys here last time!
上次是你先動手打我弟兄!
And you.
你給我出來.
My brother said you're the cockiest.
我弟兄說你是最囂張的一個.
I'm the only one responsible for what happened.
這里風大雨大,一人做事一人當.
Leave my brothers out of it.
与我兄弟無關,你別碰他.
Good. You've got guts. Come on.
好,你有种,給我出來.
-Hey. Are you sure about this? -Yes!
-喂. 你行不行呀? -行!
-Are you all right? -Well? How are you?
-怎么樣…? -哥哥你怎么了?
Hey. Are you all right?
喂. 怎么了?
Got any cigarettes?
有沒有煙啊?
Are you sure you're all right?
還行吧?
-Hey. Where did the bean go? -That's right.
-喂. 那顆黃豆去哪了? -好吧.
Let's go.
走.
Are you really okay?
喂,你真的沒事啊?
What's wrong with your butt, brother?
哥哥,你的屁股怎么了?
Are you sure?
真的沒事?
First, watch my hands. Then watch how my legs move.
單刀看手,雙刀看走
Here we go.
來了
''Snow covers the hilItop''!
"雪花蓋頂"!
''Rhino looks at the Moon''!
"犀牛望月"!
''Chain of sleeping dragons''!
"再來,縮龍成寸"!
Fishball Ming!
魚蛋明!
Come. Repeat my moves.
過來,耍給我看看
All right.
來.
Ready? ''Snow covers the hilItop''!
先來, "雪花蓋頂"!
''Rhino looks at the Moon''!
"犀牛望月"!
''Chain of sleeping dragons''!
"縮龍成寸"!
Stop!
停!
Stand right there.
你給我站住著.
What kind of a stance was that?
這是什么馬步?
It looks more like Wing Chun than Hung Gar!
你來學洪拳,卻打詠春?
Give me the knives.
把刀還給我
You must've seen the film ''Hung Gar and Wing Chun''
我猜你一定是去看那部《洪拳和詠春》
and got your stances all screwed up!
搞得馬步亂七八糟!
I've told you! Those movies are nothing but lies!
我跟你們說了,電影是騙人的!
The Hung Gar and Wing Chun styles are totally different,
洪拳是洪拳,詠春是詠春,
not like in the movie!
哪會像電影那樣
They mixed them all up. It's a mess!
不倫不類,一塌糊涂!
-Master. -What?
-師父. -干嘛?
That movie just opened yesterday
那部戲昨天才上映的
and you've already seen it?
你這么快就看了?
What did you say?
你說什么?
How dare you interrupt me while I'm talking?!
師父說話你敢頂嘴?
Where's your discipline?
膽子不小,沒大沒小
Go over there and do the horse stance for two hours!
到牆角扎兩個鐘頭馬
From now on, if l find anyone learning those
以后你們哪個去看那些電影
messed up kung fu moves from the movies,
學了不三不四的功夫回來 讓我知道的話
I'll break his legs!
我一定打斷你們的腿
Deep horse stance, all of you!
全部站好,給我扎個四平馬
You can't leave until you get it right!
扎不好別走!扎馬!
What the hell is wrong with you?
你剛才搞什么鬼啊?
I haven't shit for days!
我好几天拉不出屎了!
I'm leaving early.
待會儿我先回去了.
Is Ming okay?
魚蛋明沒事吧?
He doesn't look good. Is he sick?
他臉色很差,不舒服啊?
Him?
他?
Yes, he's sick.
哦對,他不舒服
But...
不過...
He'll feel better if you ask him yourself.
如果你直接問他,他可能會舒服一些
Actually, I meant to ask you.
其實呢,我有件事想問問你的.
Why do you two want to learn kung fu?
為什么你們想要來學功夫?
It's normal for boys to want to learn kung fu.
男孩子學功夫很平常, 沒什么大不了的.
Why do you ask?
干嘛問這個?
Nothing.
沒什么啊.
You two don't look like the kung fu type.
我看你們兩個都不像是來學功夫的.
He wants to learn drumming,
一個呢,就要學打鼓.
and you the Butterfly Knives.
一個呢,就要學蝴蝶刀,
Then why do you learn kung fu? You're a girl.
你是女孩子家,干嘛學功夫啊?
I don't know either.
我也不知道呀.
My dad had always wanted me to learn it.
從小我爸就要我跟他學功夫了.
He said he wants to glorify the Chinese Martial Arts.
他說,是想把中國的武術發揚光大.
My mom was a real chivalrous lady.
我媽媽才是俠女.
Her rank is even higher than my dad's.
她的輩份比我爸爸還要高
Her grandfather was the founder of Yang style Tai Chi.
她是太极宗師楊露禪的孫女
My dad really loved my mom.
我爸爸很喜歡我媽媽的
But she got ill and passed away
不過我媽媽嫁給我爸爸以后
not long after I was born.
生下我不久就病死了
You're ranked pretty high then!
那豈不是你輩份更高?
I sure am!
是挺高的!
Hey.
對了
Do you have a girIfriend?
你有沒有女朋友啊?
It's gone.
已經走了.
Are...are you free tomorrow?
你...明天有沒有空?
My God. How could this happen?
真可怜,怎么會這樣啊?
Step aside! Mind your own business!
讓讓...你顧你自己吧!
Hou! What's going on?
小猴子,什么事啊?
Don't you know?
你不知道什么事嗎?
Ming went crazy at home
魚蛋明在家瘋了...
and started biting his whole family!
...把全家人都咬傷了!
His brother called the cops. They're taking him to the hospital now.
幸虧他弟弟去報警, 現在送他去醫院.
I'll be back, Grandma.
奶奶,我出去一下.
I bought two tickets for the 5:30 show.
我買了兩張電影票.
''A TOUCH OF ZEN''
"俠女"
Ming!
魚蛋明!
Are you all right?
你沒事吧?
The doctor said I've got rabies.
醫生說我感染鼠疫.
I'll be staying here for a while.
要留院一星期.
We shouldn't play with rats anymore.
我們以后還是別玩老鼠了.
Rabies? That's it?
鼠疫而已
Why were you so worried just now?
你剛才慌慌張張的干什么啊?
Nothing.
哦,沒事啊.
And...don't tell Chivalrous Lady.
還有啊...你別告訴俠女啊.
I'll write to her myself.
我自己會寫信給她的.
You get some rest.
好,那你休息吧.
I'm going now.
我走了.
You know what?
喂,你知道嗎?
I think I'm really in love with Chivalrous Lady.
我發現自己真的愛上俠女了.
I used to get aroused whenever l was near her.
我以前一靠近她那儿, 就已經有反應了.
But now I'm lying here,
但是我現在躺在床上,
and I get aroused just thinking about her.
光是想著她,就已經.
I wonder...is that love?
不知道這些算不算是愛情啊?
I guess.
我想算吧.
But...try not to think too much.
不過...可是你別想那么多了.
It's not good for you.
傷身体啊.
Have you seen her lately?
你最近有沒有見過她?
Chivalrous Lady? No. No.
俠女?沒有...沒有啊
I'm going now. Don't think too much.
我走了,多休息,別胡思亂想了.
Why're you in such a hurry?
喂,你急著去哪啊?
It's getting dark. I think...
天快黑了,我想...
I think she's about to come out.
...她也快出來了.
You're going to look for that ghost again?
你又去找那個女鬼啊?
Fate!
冤孽!
Fate indeed!
真是冤孽!
What are you doing here?
干嘛你來這里啊?
I want to see you.
我想要見你.
You hurt your hand!
你的手受傷了!
I will get you out of here.
我一定會帶你离開這儿.
Are you taking a shower, sister?
小妹,你是不是在洗澡?
Yes!
是!
''That light smile on your face
"梨渦淺笑
are you aware of its magic?
可知否奧妙
It stirs my lonely heart
寂寞深鎖暗動搖
and takes my spirits away
魂消魄蕩身飄渺
I am trapped. How can I be with you?
被困扰 怎得共渡藍橋
That light smile on your face
梨渦輕照
shines like a moon
映出花月調
I hope that we can always be together
但望相看慰寂寥
and share every second and minute
時刻与共享分秒
I wish we will always be a pair of lovebirds
愿折腰 今生效同林鳥
That light smile on your face
梨渦淺笑
has already locked my heart
似把君邀
Dreams fill my heart and mind
綺夢輕泛浪潮
as I think about you til dawn
春宵猶未覺曉
That cute smile on your face
梨渦雖俏
encompasses both sadness and joy
悲歡竟逆料
But sometimes, love can turn to hate
樂极痴戀變恨苗
and hearts can be broken in an instant
情絲寸斷一朝了
The dream is now over, and she's no longer here
夢已消 花依舊玉人渺
That light smile on your face
梨渦淺笑
has already locked my heart
似把君邀
Dreams fill my heart and mind
綺夢輕泛浪潮
as I think about you til dawn
春宵猶未覺曉
That cute smile on your face
梨渦雖俏
encompasses both sadness and joy...''
悲歡竟逆料..."
Boss! Is it a boy or a girl?
老大,是儿子還是女儿?
-Boy, boy! -All right!
-儿子, 儿子! -好哦!
I'm fine!
沒事!
Cheers!
干杯!
God damn it!
干你娘啊!
''The dream is now over, and she's no longer here''
"夢已消 花依舊玉人渺"
You wrote all these letters?
這些信全是你寫的?
All the stories sounded like movie synopses.
為什么信里面寫的 那么像電影里的情節?
Really?
是嗎?
Well, life is just like in the movies.
人生如戲,戲如人生嘛.
You copied them! Just admit it!
你抄就抄啦,干嘛不承認?
I don't care. As long as I can convince you.
天下文章一大抄嘛!
Did I say I am convinced?
神經病,我才不接受呢,
I think they're disgusting.
肉麻死了.
But they're all from my heart!
這些全是我的真心話!
Why are you holding a sword?
咦,你干嘛拿著劍啊?
Your body is weak, so I wanted to teach you the Tai Chi Sword style.
你身体那么弱, 我打算教你一套太极劍嘛
That's good. Hung Gar is too difficuIt for me.
太好了, 以后不用那么辛苦去學洪拳
Tai Chi is much better!
太极比較好,太极好
Watch it! Or I'll chop your hand off!
你找死,當心我砍掉你的手
You wouldn't! I just got out of the hospital!
我今天才出院,你舍得嗎?
Don't wet your pants now.
對准點…別把褲子弄濕了
Hey, Sugar Cane Boy! Taking a piss?
嘿,賣甘蔗的,撒尿啊?
Let me pull up your pants for you.
好了…來…我幫你穿上褲子
Let's go back to the movies.
尿完了沒有? 尿完了我們回去看電影
What's that? What's that??
這是什么? 這是什么?
I'm asking you! What's that??
我問你,這是什么啊?
So you're the one who shot me over the years!
原來用彈弓打我十年的人就是你
You killed my dad! I must avenge him!
你殺死我爸,我還沒替他報仇呢
Are you nuts? I killed your dad?
我什么時候殺你爸了? 你是不是神經病?
I didn't kill him. He killed himself.
你爸爸是自殺的,不是我殺的
Everyone in Cheung Chau knows that!
整個長洲都知道
He lost all his money gambling.
他欠了一屁股債,賭輸了錢
The cops were investigating him and he had nowhere to go.
被人逼債,無路可走
He killed himself out of fear, you idiot!
他畏罪自殺,傻小子
Dad didn't kill himself! He was murdered!
我爸不是自殺的,他是被人謀殺的
He was a highly decorated officer, a good cop!
他一向很勇敢,他是個好警察
You killed him! Just admit it!
是你把他殺了的,你還不認?
Listen, kid.
小子
You think it's easy to kill someone?
你以為殺人很簡單?
Like it is in the movies?
你以為是在看電影?
I haven't even stepped on an ant!
我長這么大 連螞蟻也沒踩死過一只!
I saw you crush a frog with my own eyes!
我親眼看見你踩死一只田雞的!
When have I ever crushed a frog?
我什么時候踩死一只田雞了?
You've gone crazy from thinking about your dad!
我看你想你爸想瘋了!
Fine.
好.
Here's your chance. Kill me, if you dare.
我給你一次机會,有种你就殺了我.
Come on! Kill me! Kill me!!
來,殺!
What?
怎么?
One day, I will kill you!
我肯定會宰了你!
You just wait and see!
你等著!
Kill me? You wouldn't have the guts!
我看你是吃了熊心豹子膽了! 想殺我?
My son is with me today.
要不是我今天帶著孩子
Otherwise, I would've cut your balls off!
我不把你同了我不叫大喪!殺了我?
I stepped on a frog 10 years ago and he even remembers that?
媽的,記性這么好! 我十年前踩死田雞他都記得
Have you heard the news? Fan is going to have a duel with Crazy!
你知道嗎,阿凡要跟大喪決斗?
What?? When?
什么?什么時候?
In two nights, at the temple!
后天晚上,在大廟
''TWIN DRAGONS''
"雙龍出海"
Fan!
阿凡!
What's with him?
他怎么了?
He's been punching the bag ever since he got here.
一上來就什么都不說, 不停地打沙包
He says he and Crazy are going to have a duel.
他說要跟大喪決斗.
-A duel? -Yes!
-決斗? -是啊!
You can punch a bag, but can you beat him?
你打沙包還可以,你打得過他嗎?
Think you'll win after just a few lessons?
學了兩下就能打贏人家?
I don't want to win! I'm just not afraid of him anymore!!
我不是要贏,我是不想再怕他!
WE are afraid! You're going to die!
你這樣是送死,我們更怕
I can fight in your place! I'm a better fighter!
要打我替你去打,我身手比你好!
Or we can ask Chivalrous Lady!
要不就叫俠女去打!
JUST LEAVE ME ALONE!!
別管我行不行?
Beat me. Then you can do whatever you want.
你能打贏我,我們就不管你
I'm warning you!
你還來?
Why did you hit him so hard?
你干嘛出手這么重啊?
He knows why.
他知道的.
He does? But I don't!
他知道?我怎么不知道?
Don't call me ''Chivalrous Lady'' anymore.
以后不要再提"俠女"這兩個字.
Mr. Turtle. You're always hiding in your shell.
烏龜…你整天躲在殼里面
Aren't you bored?
你悶不悶?
Have you been to Hong Kong?
你到過香港沒有?
Have you seen the outside world?
你知不知道外面的世界是怎么樣的?
Bishop!
飛"相"!
Mayor, I've heard that the kid trains in Hung Gar.
喂,村長,听說那個小子是學洪拳的.
His Master is Gok Bill!
他師父葛彪可厲害了!
He made this really vicious looking lion head
去年舞獅,黑面青鼻鐵角爛耳朵擦須
at last year's Lion Dance!
不知道有多凶!
So? Crazy studied Choy Li Fut!
嘿,大喪以前是學蔡李佛的!
He's much more experienced than that kid!
論輩份,比那小子要高得多!
But still!
話可不能這么說啊
''A blind fist can kill the Old Master''
正所謂"瞎貓撞死耗子嘛"
That's right! Haven't you heard?
可不是,你沒有听說過嗎?
''Youth exceIs at fists, and elder exceIs in weapons''!
"拳怕少壯,棍怕老郎!"
Oh, yeah?
嘿, 我沒有听過?
What are the 5 best styles of Southern Boxing?
南拳最出色的是哪五家,你知道嗎?
There are 5??
南拳有五家嗎?
Of course! I'll tell you!
當然有,我告訴你啊
They're Hung, Lau, Choy, Lee, and Mok!
就是洪、劉、蔡、李、莫, 听過沒有啊?
So which is better? Choy Li Fut or Hung Gar?
是蔡李佛厲害還是洪拳厲害?
I'll tell you.
你這种態度,我告訴你吧.
Hung Hei-kwun founded Hung Gar,
洪拳的開山祖就是洪熙官,
and Chan Heung founded Choy Li Fut.
而蔡李佛的開山祖就是陳享.
Cut the bullshit!
聊了這么久!
So are you betting on Crazy or the kid?
-你究竟買大喪贏還是那個小子贏? -你買誰?
That's right!
哦...
Checkmate!
...將軍!
Master knows about us.
師父知道了我跟你的事.
I may never see you again.
我怕以后再也見不到你了.
Will you take me away tonight?
今晚能不能帶我走?
I'll wait for you at the pier. Don't forget.
我在碼頭等你,記住呀
Have some more.
吃菜,乖.
Thanks.
謝謝.
You too.
你也多吃點.
Have some more.
多吃點.
I'm going, Grandma.
奶奶,我走了.
Take this. It's going to rain tonight.
今天晚上會下雨,帶著吧
Come back soon. It's the Moon Festival.
早點回來. 拜月亮啊(中秋節).
You've got to win, Brother Fan.
凡哥,你一定要贏啊
Fan!
阿凡!
You won't lose with these.
這兩把刀是不會讓你輸的
Looks like Brother Crazy won't be coming.
看來大喪哥是不敢來啦
He probably doesn't want to bully a kid.
他可能不想欺負小孩吧?
Maybe he doesn't dare to come!
也許大喪哥是不敢來!
He's 20 years older!
老實說他比那小子大二十多歲
It's going to be hard on him.
打起來很吃虧
What's with Brother Crazy? Is he drunk?
有沒有搞錯啊? 大喪哥喝醉了?
Maybe it's the Drunken Sword Style!
不像,可能是醉關刀!
Kick his ass!
刺他胸口!
Chop his head off!
快砍他…劈他的頭!
Fight him, Fan!
砍他, 阿凡!
What the hell was that?
怎么搞的,搞什么?
-Doesn't he know how to fight? -What's with Brother Crazy tonight?
-真不知道他會不會打? -今晚大喪他怎么了?
-Maybe he hasn't eaten. -He's totally not in his element!
-好像沒吃飯一樣. -根本完全沒有進入狀態!
-Brother Crazy!
-大哥...醒醒!
-Are you all right? -Hold on!
-沒事吧? -醒醒!
After him!
追他!
Come back!
別追了!
Let him go.
讓他走吧.
I thought you wouldn't come!
我以為你不來了!
It's okay now. Let's go.
沒事了,我們走.
Where are we going?
去哪里?
To Hong Kong.
去香港.
Fan! Fan!
阿凡! 阿凡!
Fan!!
阿凡!!
Crazy is still alive!
大喪還沒死!
Crazy! He...
大喪他...
What?
什么?
Nothing. Go!
沒事了,你走吧!
And don't come back!
走了別再回來了!
Take care of my Grandma!
替我照顧我奶奶
I will!
行啦!
Hello?
喂?
Hello? Fan?
喂? 阿凡?
Can you come back this Saturday?
你這星期六有沒有空回來一趟?
What is it? I'm busy here.
什么事?我現在工作很忙
Why don't you come out here?
不如你出來找我吧?
I'll tell you when you come back.
回來再說吧.
It's urgent. Just come back.
有要緊事,回來吧.
Fine. That's it then.
好吧...就這樣
How did this happen?
怎么會這樣?
He died of a brain tumor.
大喪得腦瘤死了.
I thought I...
他是不是被我...
He lost to you on purpose that night.
那天晚上,是故意輸給你的.
We heard that he couldn't bear to leave his son behind.
听說大喪很舍不得他儿子.
He asked someone to tell me before he died
他臨死前托人叫我告訴你
that he really didn't kill your dad.
他真的沒有殺你爸爸.
half.
一半.
half?
一半?
All right, half.
好,一半.
Son.
儿子...
Here, son. Have a smoke.
儿子,來一根吧.
I'll never be able to smoke with you.
爸爸以后沒机會跟你坐在一塊抽煙了.
Open your mouth.
張開嘴巴.
What do you want to do when you grow up?
你有沒有想過長大以后干什么啊?
I don't know.
我不知道.
Just don't be a nobody, like your dad.
千万別像你爸爸這么沒出息.
Study hard.
多讀點書.
Go to Hong Kong and become an office clerk.
到香港找份寫字樓的工作.
It's a good job. It's classy, and it pays well.
寫字樓好,又高尚又能賺錢.
People respect you in a suit.
穿套西裝人人都看得起你.
Don't be a Cheung Chau gangster for life.
你難道一輩子留在長洲游嗎?
Didn't we come here to play the last time?
爸爸,我以前在這里玩過?
Yes, we came here to play last time.
是,上次來這里玩過
But Daddy won't be able to do that with you anymore.
是,爸爸以后沒机會和你一塊玩了
Don't miss Daddy even if Daddy is not here.
爸爸不在,不用惦記爸爸
Nothing is too hard to handle.
天塌下來當被子蓋
You're a man. You can't do great things if you're a sissy!
你是男孩子,婆婆媽媽怎么做大事?
Hey. It's not your fault.
對,与你無關的.
Your slingshots didn't cause his tumor.
腦瘤和挨彈珠是沒有關聯的.
I've held two tickets for you, Master Gok.
留了兩張票給你了,葛師父.
Thanks.
謝謝.
You're welcome.
不客气.
-$7? -Thanks.
-七塊? -謝謝.
Like this?
這樣?
No, like this!
不是,這樣!
Bravo! That was good!
好!
Do you know?
你知道嗎?
Hou went to Holland with his dad.
小猴子跟他爸爸去了荷蘭.
Really?
是嗎?
Now the Temple is all quiet.
現在大廟每天晚上都是冷冷清清的.
Those gangsters all went to Hong Kong,
那幫家伙全去了香港
and they all became killers.
都當了殺手.
Remember Crazy's best fighter, Fo-tan?
跟大喪景能打的那個火炭?
I saw him in the news the other day
我前天看電視才知道...
when he was arrested.
...他被抓了
Murder. He got almost 20 years.
殺人,判了十多年
How's your Chivalrous Lady?
對了,你那個俠女呢?
She's doing good.
挺好
She wants to have a drink with you sometime.
她說如果有空出來喝一杯
Also, she wants to apologize for hurting you.
還有,她說那天把你打傷了不好意恩
Stay and do the Lion Dance at the Tin Hau Festival with me!
今年天后誕籮獅,我算你一份
Didn't you like watching her drumming?
你不是喜歡看俠女打鼓嗎?
Well? What about that ghost of yours?
怎么了,你的女鬼呢?
Her?
她?
She left.
走了
She left?
走了?
Why?
為什么?
I don't know.
我也不知道為什么
She took me to this Buddhist Temple one day.
有一天,她突然說帶我去佛堂拜佛
She said she wanted to pray for me.
說是為我祈福
But when I came out, she was gone.
但拜完出來后,她就不見了
So she Is a ghost after all!
不是這么恐怖吧?
After she left, I took her turtle back
她走了以后,我把她留下的烏龜
to her old nunnery.
送到她以前的尼姑庵
Perhaps...
也許...
She just wanted to fly away.
她只是想飛出去
Fan, I'll come back for you!
阿凡,我會回來找你的
I just want to see this world!
我想看看這個世界
I will come back for you!
我一定會回來找你
Hey! Have you had lunch yet?
吃飯了沒有?